24小时
第三季  第17集
前情提要
有多少病毒被散播?
How much of the virus was released?
足以让整栋楼的人丧命
Enough to kill everyone in the building.
其它地方还有没有?
Did you plant any other vials?
我的目标只是这个酒店
My assignment was the hotel.
-这么说还有  -对 11个
-So there are others.  -Yes, eleven.
阿尔弗斯在通风系统里放了装有科迪利亚病毒的瓶子
Alvers planted a vial containing the cordilla virus in the ventilation system.
在盖尔试图解除的时候 病毒释放了
It went off as Gael was trying to disarm it.
一个人也不能从这离开
No one can be allowed to leave the building.
必须实施全封闭隔离
We have to impose a total quarantine.
如果人们发现了怎么回事 会引发大范围恐慌的
If these people realize what's going on, there will be widespread panic.
他们骗了我们
They are lying to us.
是酒店里面出了问题
It's inside the building.
不要靠近大门 回来
Keep away from the doors. Stay back.
如果你再试图离开 我就开枪
If you try to leave, I will shoot you.
不 你不会的
No, you won't.
他认识你 杰克
He knows who you are, Jack.
谁?
Who knows who I am?
别跟我提杰克·鲍尔
Don't presume to tell me about Jack Bauer.
这是他说的
That's what he said.
如果你跟他作对 你死定了
If you go against him, you're a dead man.
我是鲍尔
This is Bauer.
你好 杰克
Hello Jack.
我知道你比阿马多尔技高一筹 但是...
I knew you were better than Amador, but...
你不见得比我强
you are not better than me.
我要你帮我联系你的一个朋友
I need you to put me in touch with a friend of yours.
总统先生 持有科迪利亚病毒的人想和您谈谈
Mr President, the man in possession of the Cordilla virus has demanded to speak with you.
你已无力控制你的国家
You are no longer in control of your country,
如果你不竭尽全力满足我的要求
and if you do not use the full power of your office to execute my wishes
我会继续释放病毒 一切将无法控制
the virus will be released, and it will be impossible to stop.
以下事件发生于凌晨5点至6点之间
The following takes place between 5:00 am and 6:00 am.
大家听着 冷静
Everybody, stay calm.
冷静一下 安静
Stay calm and quiet.
快看 外面!
Look, outside!
我要你们明白一件事
I want to make one thing clear right now.
在另行通知之前 任何人不准离开这栋楼
No one leaves this building until further notice.
稍后
In a moment,
我会在广播上声明并解释
I will get on the intercom and explain why.
我需要绝对的安静和配合
I need absolute quiet and absolute cooperation.
整个酒店都能听到?
It reaches the entire hotel?
是
Yes.
我是联邦探员米歇尔·德斯勒
This is federal agent Michelle Dessler.
为了应付当前的形势
In order to survive what's happened,
你们必须听仔细 并按照我说的做
you will need to listen carefully, and follow my instructions.
正如你们所知道的
As most of you already know,
有人在酒店内释放了传染性物质
an infectious substance has been released in the building
酒店已被隔离
and the hotel has been quarantined.
我们会不惜一切阻止擅自离开酒店的人
Anyone attempting to leave will be stopped by any means necessary.
如果你在房间里 待在里面
If you are in your room, stay there.
在外面的 立刻回到房间里
If you are anywhere else, return to your room immediately.
医护人员马上就到
Medical assistance will arrive shortly, and be given to anyone who requires it.
现在最重要的是回到自己的房间里 别出门
The first priority is to go back to your room and stay there.
谢谢
Thank you.
好吧 各位 你们都听到了
Ok, folks, you heard the announcement.
回到电梯里去
Let's make our way back to the elevators.
电梯已经恢复正常
The elevators are back in operation.
请这边走 各位
This way, people.
请保持秩序
In an orderly fashion, please.
请回到电梯里
Make your way to the elevators.
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
丹尼?
Danny?
丹尼 哦 不
Danny, oh, no.
哦 哦 天哪
Oh, oh, God.
谁干的?
Who did this?
是谁杀了他?
Who killed him?
你?
You?
你是一名联邦探员
You are a federal agent.
你本该保护他
You were supposed to protect him.
放开我
Get your hands off me.
你必须冷静
You are going to have to calm down.
我很抱歉 但你这样只会让事情更糟
I am sorry, but this is just going to make things worse.
你本该保护他
You were supposed to protect him.
我是鲍尔 请讲
Yes, this is Bauer.
鲍尔探员 请稍等 总统的电话
Agent Bauer, Please hold for the president.
杰克
Jack.
总统先生
Mr President.
刚才和我通话的 那个持有病毒的人
The man I spoke to, the one who controls this virus.
为什么他会通过你找到我?
Why did he use you to get to me?
我也想知道 先生
I wish I could answer that, sir.
他说他认识我 但目前
He says he knows me, but right now we haven't been able
我们还不能确定他的身份
to ascertain a positive identification.
现在我唯一确定的是
The only thing I can tell you for certain is that
上一小时内他人在洛杉矶
within the last hour, he was in Los Angeles.
杰克.
Jack
他名目张胆的告诉我
He made it clear
他想通过病毒威胁控制我
that he intends to use the threat of releasing this virus to control me
并通过我控制整个国家
and through me the entire apparatus of our national government.
绝对不能让他得逞
Obviously, we can't let that happen.
我明白 先生
I understand, sir.
找到他 杰克
Find him, Jack.
我们会想尽一切办法
We are doing everything we can.
我会随时向您汇报
I will keep in touch.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿马多尔一死 我们只剩两条线索了
With Amador dead, we've got two leads left.
第一 不管他是谁 他声称认识我
First, whoever this guy is, he says he knows me.
第二 他认识阿尔弗斯
Second, he knows Alvers.
在酒店里放病毒的人?
The guy who planted the virus at the hotel?
对
That's right.
打电话给托尼
I want you to call Tony.
告诉他从阿尔弗斯口中问出这个人的体貌体征 越详细越好
Tell him to get Alvers to give us a physical description as detailed as possible.
还有彻底检查我所有的工作档案中涉及到的人
then I want to cross check with the personnel in my service file.
鲍尔说他不知道此人是谁
Bauer says he doesn't know who this man is.
但他认识鲍尔
But he knows Bauer.
很显然
Apparently.
大卫 这怎么可能?
David, how is that possible?
我不知道 韦恩 我只知道
I don't know, Wayne, all I know is,
他们会竭尽所能找到他
they're doing everything they can to find this man.
他有没有暗示鲍尔他到底要什么?
Did he give Bauer any indication of what he wants?
没有
No.
但他持有的病毒
But he controls enough of the virus to wipe out
足以屠杀全国大部分的人
a significant portion of this country's population.
所以 不管他想怎么样
So, whatever he wants,
我们别无选择 只能听从
we don't have much choice but to give it to him.
至少现在是这样
At least for now.
确定所有出口都被封锁
Make sure all the exits are sealed off.
我刚检查过
I just checked a few minutes ago.
那就再查一次
Well, check again.
你不必打发我 德斯勒探员
You don't have to keep me busy, agent Dessler.
我不会恐慌的
I am not going to panic.
我知道你不会
I know you won't.
我很感激你给予我的帮助
I appreciate all the help you have given me.
我想知道真相
I'd just like to know the truth.
酒店内的所有人都会死吗?
Is everyone in this hotel going to die?
不是
Not everyone.
有些人会对病毒免疫
A few will be immune to the virus.
但绝大部分会死
But most of us.
要怎么样才能幸存?
What are the chances of survival?
我不清楚
I don't know.
我知道了会立刻告诉你
I will let you know as soon as I do.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是德斯勒
Dessler.
嘿 是我
Hey, it's me.
警戒带已经设好了
The perimeters are set.
很好 现在场面基本控制住了
Good. Things are under control right now,
但人们陆续出现病症 还是会带来恐慌
but a panic is still possible as more people start showing symptoms.
对 病毒的潜伏期远比我们想的短
Yeah, we have to be ready for that especially since
我们得做好准备
the incubation period of the virus is so much shorter than we thought it was.
你怎么样?
How are you doing?
到目前为止 我还好
I am fine so far.
我只是有点...
I just...
怎么了?
What?
这一切太疯狂了
Things go crazy.
我不得不向一个男人开枪
I had to shoot a man.
他想逃出酒店
He was trying to get out of the hotel.
他死了
He is dead.
米歇尔
Michelle,
你只是做你应该做的 在那种情况下你只能这么做
you did what you had to do, the only thing you could have done.
你必须集中精神 好吗?
You need to stay focused, all right?
我知道 我会的
I know, I am
好 还有些事要你去办
All right, there's something we need you to do.
我们得知道阿尔弗斯是否曾见过他的雇主
We need you to find out if Alvers ever saw the man that hired him.
让他描述一下 越详细越好
We need a description as detailed as possible.
我这就去办
I am on it.
我等会打给你
I will call you right back.
快 所有人 来
Come on, everyone, move it.
我在出血
I am bleeding.
看起来还可以
You don't look too bad so far.
我们说好了的
We had a deal.
我说出了你们想知道的
I told you what I knew.
我一出现病症 你就得杀了我
You'd kill me when I start showing symptoms.
你还没有说出你所知道的一切
You haven't told us everything you know.
你说什么?
What are you talking about?
你的老板 他叫什么?
The man you work for, what's his name?
他从没告诉我他的名字
He's never told me his name.
我就要死了 我没必要撒谎
I am dying, I have nothing to gain by lying about it.
上一次见到他是什么时候?
When was the last time you saw him?
3个小时前 在唐人街的Go会所
Three hours ago, at a Go parlor in Chinatown.
托尼 我正在审问阿尔弗斯
Tony, I am with Alvers.
准备好了 开始把
We are ready, go ahead.
描述一下他的样子
I want a description.
30多岁 白种人
Mid 30s, Caucasian,
身高约六尺一寸 黑头发 眼睛褐色 有点瘦 没有胡须
about six-one, black hair, brown eyes, lean, no facial hair.
英国口音
He speaks with a British accent.
都清楚了吗?
You got that?
嗯 听清了
Yeah, we got it.
要多长时间?
How long is this going to take?
所有特征录入后 应该不会太久
Once the parameters are in, not long.
我需要对照所有杰克过去接触过的人
I just need to cross reference it with personnel that Jack has worked with in the past.
杰克 我把疑犯的照片传给你
All right, Jack, we uploading the photos for the suspects.
你看一下
You should have a visual
明白
Copy that.
没有
He is not there
你肯定?
Are you sure?
我肯定
Of course I am sure.
托尼
Tony
我听见了
Yeah, I heard
我们应该扩大查找范围
We are going to have to widen the search parameters.
他的口音也许误导了我们
The accent might be a mislead.
也许他不是英国人
Maybe he is not even British.
如果剔出这个参数 数据会增加50倍
If we drop that parameter, the database will increase by a factor of almost 50.
有750个嫌疑人
That's 750 possibilities.
很多人的可靠影像都丢失了
And a fair number of those are missing reliable visuals.
换句话说 没有面部照片
In other words, no head shots.
托尼
Tony.
怎么说 杰克
Yeah, Jack.
除了口音和面部特征外 你们怎么设置查找范围的?
What are the parameters for the search outsisde of accent and appearance?
尽量广的范围 所有活着的男性...
As wide as we could make them. All living males...
改一下
Change that.
把活着的改掉?
Change living?
对 改成猜测已身亡的
Yeah, change it to presumed dead.
收到
Copy that.
不是... 不是...
No... No...
是他 就是他
There. That's him.
托尼 托尼 是他
Tony, Tony, that's him.
杰克 你认识这家伙吗?
Jack, you know this guy?
我的天
My god.
杰克?
Jack?
对 我认识他
Yeah, I know him.
他叫斯蒂芬 桑德斯
His name is Stephen Saunders.
英国情报局曾派他到反恐局来协助我们执行在科索沃的任务
British intelligence lent him to CTU for a mission in Kosovo.
针对维克托里·德拉赞的那次
The one that target Victory Drazen.
对
Yeah.
我是唯一一个逃生的 包括桑德斯在内其他五人全部身亡
I was the only one to get out, five other died including Saunders.
至少我这么认为
At least that's what I thought.
我大错特错了
I was obviously wrong.
托尼 我马上回去找你
Tony, I am going to have to get back to you.
我需要时间从头到尾仔细想想
I need a few minutes to think this through.
杰克 抓紧时间
Jack, hurry.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
酒店的局势已经被控制住
The situation at the hotel seems to be under control.
特警队已经到位
Now SWAT is in place.
卫生部的人也到了 正准备开始检疫
NHS is there, and will start the testing procedures soon.
有没有任何风声传到媒体那里?
Any sense that the press has picked up on this?
没 大卫 目前为止没有
No, David, not so far.
但他们不久肯定会知道
But they are bound to before long.
病毒的情况要隐瞒
Containing the virus is crucial,
酒店的事故也不能泄漏
but containing the story that it was released in the hotel is just as important.
假如消息传了出去 我们需要一些说辞
If the story breaks, we'll need a plausible cover.
我再想些应对言辞
I will work up some scenarios.
别提 "科迪利亚病毒" 这个名词
Don't use the term "Cordilla Virus".
人们没听说过 陌生的名字会带来更多恐慌
People have never heard of it, and the unknown creates more fear.
就说它和军团病病症差不多
Say it's similar to Legionaire's Disease.
人们对这个比较熟悉 知道它能被成功控制
People are familiar with that, and they know it was handled successfully.
好
Ok.
奥劳林先生
Mr O'Laughlin.
总统先生
Mr President.
请进
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
帕默尔先生
Mr Palmer.
尚有11管病毒下落不明
11 vials of the virus are unaccounted for.
国土安全部有什么建议?
What's homeland security's assessment?
先生 我们认为警报等级应上升至红色
Sir, we believe the threat level should be raised to red.
可以 国内航空呢?
Do it. What about domestic air travel?
我们建议取消所有航班 封锁机场
It is our suggestion that flights be grounded and airports be closed.
总统先生 如果您想避免产生恐慌
Mr President, if your concern is to avoid panic,
关闭机场可能会适得其反
stopping air traffic might have the opposite effect.
这总比让病毒肆虐的好
That's better than allowing a widespread release of the virus.
如果关闭机场
If you shut down those airports,
你就无法用军团病搪塞媒体
you won't be able to explain it away with Legionnaire's Disease.
我们讨论的是安全问题 总统先生
We are talking about security issues, Mr President,
而不是公众关系
we are not talking about public relations.
公众的反映本身就是一种安全问题
And how the public relates to this is a security issue.
总统先生 我们还建议停止洲际铁路及公交车运行...
Mr President, we'd also advocate shutting down interstate rail and bus traffic in the interest of...
听着 持有病毒的人可能已经在车上了
Listen. Whoever has these vials could already be in their cars.
现在 我们不能封闭所有的公路
Now, we can't shut down every single highway.
总统先生
Mr President.
先生们
Gentleman.
通知所有机场做好预警 随时准备全国性封闭
Alert the airlines to a possible nationwide shutdown,
等候我的命令
but wait for my authorization.
是
Yes, sir.
Yes.
总统先生 有您的电话在一号线
Mr President, I have a call on one.
稍等一下
One moment, please.
谢谢你 奥劳林先生
Thank you. Mr O'Laughlin.
谢谢您 总统先生
Thank you, Mr President.
是他
It's him.
好 就是这个 开始追踪
Okay, that's it here we go, start the trace.
-请帮我接通  -是 先生 马上
-Put the call through, please.  -Yes Sir, right away.
总统先生?
Mr President?
是我
Yes.
现在我要你为我做第一件事
It's time for your first assignment,
很简单 但这关系到我们将来的合作
a very simple one, but one necessary to our future relationship.
你我不存在交情
We don't have a relationship.
不 你不能和恐怖份子谈条件
No, you don't negotiate with terrorists.
我不和你讨价还价 就按我说的做
Well, I don't negotiate with heads of state, so just do as you are told.
你们大厦街对面有个邮箱
Across the street from your building is a mailbox.
让特勤处的人打开它
Have the Secret Service open it.
里面有个用黑纸包着的包裹
Inside is a package wrapped in black paper.
让他们在10分钟之内拿给你
Have them bring it to you within 10 minutes.
我不会做任何事 除非你告诉我谁...
I am not doing anything until you tell me exactly who...
通话时间不够长
He didn't stay on long enough.
也许他知道我们试图通过电话进行追踪
Probably knew we were going to try and trace the call.
让特勤处的人去取包裹
Send Secret Service to pick up the package.
好吧 大卫 但那可能裹着炸弹和病毒
All right, David, but it's going to have to be screened for explosives and the virus.
照我说的做 确保在10分钟之内送来
Then do it. Just make sure it's back here in 10 minutes.
好吧
All right.
他的档案空白一片
His file is still inactive.
没有证据显示在科索沃任务之后他出现过
There is no evidence that shows he surfaced after Kosovo.
那么 在过去的10年里 他一直让别人误以为他已经死了
So, for the past 10 years, he has been letting everyone think he was dead.
我想不是这样
I don't think so.
不 假如当时他活了下来 他会被俘虏然后被送到当地的监狱里
No, if he survived, he'd have been captured and sent to one of their prisons for years.
杰克 当时的任务失败 也许是他的原因
Jack, if the mission had failed, maybe he was the reason.
他可能背叛了团队 假装被杀 然后叛变到对手那边
He could have betrayed the team, pretended to be killed, and gone over to the other side.
你不了解桑德斯 他是个爱国者
You don't know Saunders. He was a patriot.
他肯定遭遇了什么变故
Something else happened to him.
你在给谁打电话?
Who're you calling?
军情6处
MI-6
控制室
Operations.
我是杰克·鲍尔 请帮我转接特雷弗·汤姆林森
This is Jack Bauer, I need to speak with Trevor Tomlinson, please
稍等
One moment.
你好 杰克
Hello, Jack
特雷弗 反恐局有没有派你去调查斯蒂芬 桑德斯的档案?
Trevor, has CTU brought you up to speed on Stephen Saunders?
对 我们找到他的档案了
Yeah, we have got his file up now.
没有任何迹象显示他还活着
There's no indication that he is still alive.
相信我 他还活着 你得从头到尾仔细核查
Trust me, he is. You are going to want to do a complete forensic protocol search.
我已经查过了
That's being done as we speak.
伦敦方面有没有更多资料?
Do you think London would have any additional data?
在这方面 没 全是本地的
On something like this, no. It's local.
好吧 还有件事
Ok, one more thing.
他可能会找熟悉的信任的人合作
He's going to want to deal with people he knows, people he trusts.
看看能否找到他过去的社会关系
See if you can do a quick search on all his past contacts.
好 大多数已经失踪或者确认死亡
Right. Most of them have gone dark or they are confirmed dead.
哦 有了 这个名字 戴安娜·怀特
Oh, here is something. A name: Diana White.
在80年代末负责过洛杉矶高级别护卫任务
Ran a high class escort service in Los Angels in the late 80s.
经常与外交官 使馆工作人员等打交道
Catered to diplomats, embassy employees, that sort of thing.
很显然 她给桑德斯提供了很多情报 他们之间联络密切
Apparently, she passed a great deal of intel to Saunders, and they became very close.
甚至还曾同居过
Even lived together for a while.
她是否仍在洛杉矶?
Is she still living in Los Angels?
对 但她已不在情报部门工作了
Yes, but she's been inactive in intelligence circles for some time.
收集她所有的信息传到我的电脑上
Patch her file and every piece of information you are got on her through to my computer.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要开始检测酒店里的人
I'd like to begin testing the hotel staff.
你先来吧 这样比较好
It would be very helpful if you would go first.
-好吧  -好的
-All right.  -Ok.
你的名字?
Name please?
米歇尔·德斯勒 反恐局
Michelle Dessler, CTU.
拿着这个
Here you go.
这是什么?
What's that?
这是鼻腔取样
Ok, it's a nasal swab.
和血液检测一样可靠 而且分析速度更迅速
Every bit as reliable as a blood test, and it can be analyzed much more quickly.
有多快?
How quickly?
2小时内应该能出结果
We should have the results in two hours.
谢谢
Thank You.
下一位
Next.
-在那边  -请到这来 先生
-Right over there.  -Right over here, sir.
先生 请到这来
Sir, step over here.
没事的 先生 没什么好担心的
It's alright, sir. There's nothing to be worried about.
这个手机就是斯蒂芬 桑德斯要你拿的包裹里的东西
This phone is what was in the package from Stephen Saunders.
我们检查过了
We scanned it.
没有问题
It's clean.
不幸的是 总统先生
Unfortunately, Mr President,
里面装有分流芯片
it's built with what's called a sub-channel chip,
用来接收特殊信号以躲避追踪
designed to received a specific signal that can't be traced.
我明白了
I understand.
谢谢你 亚伦
Thank you, Aaron.
不客气
Yes, sir.
这么说从现在开始他准备用这个和我联系
So this is the way he intends to communicate from now on.
但如果我们追踪不了这个手机
And if we really can't trace the call.
我们就找不到他
We can't find him.
是我
Yes.
很好 你用了这部新手机
Good. You are using your new phone.
这是我们的秘密专线
Consider it our private line.
而且 相信你已有所了解
And, as you've no doubt been informed.
所以别再费周折来追踪我的电话
Don't bother trying to trace my calls.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
在半小时内 召开一个现场直播的记者招待会
Within the next half hour, you'll hold a televised press conference.
什么内容?
About what?
空间站计划 小麦价格 随你便
The space program, the price of wheat, it's entirely up to you.
但 你必须提到 "灭顶之灾" 这个词
But, at some point, you will use the phrase "the sky is falling. "
不管你喜不喜欢 总统先生 一定得说
Use it however you like, Mr President, but use it.
他要我召开记者招待会
He wants me to call a press conference.
什么内容都行
About what, it doesn't matter.
只要提到 "灭顶之灾" 这个词
Just use the phrase "the sky is falling" .
大卫 这是个暗语
David, it's a signal of some sort.
也许暗示一次袭击 也许一波袭击
Maybe for an attack, maybe for a wave of attacks.
也许只是显示他已经控制住了一切
Maybe it's just a signal to show that he is in control.
不管怎样 你都不能照做
Either way, you can't do it.
你不能让他随心所欲
You can't give him that kind of power.
你也清楚病毒的事
You saw what that virus does.
我看过了文件
I read the file, yeah.
就在你我谈话间 上千人正奄奄一息 韦恩
A thousand people are dying as we speak, Wayne.
这可是活生生的人命啊 就在洛杉矶
Not just in a file, but in real life, right here in Los Angeles.
大卫 我知道 但问题是...
And David, I realize that, but the problem...
但如果我不照他说的做 受害民众会上升到百万以上
But if I don't do what this man says, it will be millions.
我们得争取时间
We have to buy some time.
也许反恐局能在事情失控之前找到这个疯子
and maybe CTU can find this maniac before things get out of hand.
准备记者招待会
Call a press conference.
-好  -她在
-Yeah.  -She's there.
好的 我告诉他
thank you. I will let him know.
戴安娜·怀特在家里
Diana White is at home.
关于她有什么新的资料吗?
Have we got anything new on her?
只在她的客户方面资料丰富了些
Just more on the list of clientele she handled.
外国权贵 州政府要员
Foreign dignitaries, heads of state,
甚至梵蒂冈教廷有头有脸的人物 几乎每个净资产都在两千万美元以上
even a high ranking member of the Vatican. Most with a net worth over $20 million.
嗯 她和桑德斯的关系确实不简单
Well, her relations with Saunders make sense.
她把所有客户的名字给了他
She give him the names of her clients,
他以泄露他们秘密为由敲诈他们
he blackmails them for information by threatening to reveal who they are.
你觉得这是他的行动资金来源?
You think that's how he got the money to finance his operation?
我觉得部分是
I think that's how he financed part of it.
你了解桑德斯
You knew Saunders.
你说他是个优秀的军人
You said he was a good soldier.
你觉得发生了什么?
What do you think happened?
说实话 我不知道
To be honest with you, I don't know.
我仍然不敢相信他在波斯尼亚那场爆炸中活了下来
I still can't believe he survived the blast in Bosnia.
他肯定被俘虏了 否则 他早就该露面了
They must have captured him. Otherwise, he would have resurfaced.
他们肯定把他送进监狱 天知道折磨了多久
They would have put him in prison, tortured him for God knows how manyyears.
现在他肯定认为我们的政府应该为此负责
Now he's holding our government responsible.
但他是个英国特工
But he was a British agent.
他是被我们借用的
He was on loan to us.
那是美国主导的行动
It was a US operation.
我们抛弃了他
No, we left him behind.
我抛弃了他
I left him behind.
听着 我知道在这个病毒出现前你已经在研究它了
Look, I know you were studying this virus even before it surfaced.
这不一样
This isn't the same strain.
好吧 也许不完全一致但一定有关联 对吧?
All right, maybe not exactly the same strain, but related, right?
你肯定有研究过治疗方法 疫苗什么的
So you must have been working on a cure, a vaccine, or something.
我们进行的任何研究都是基于...
Any research we have is based upon...
听着 酒店里全都是奄奄一息的人
Look, I got a hotel full of people dying out there.
其中一个是我妻子
One of them is my wife.
别告诉我你什么办法也没有
So, don't tell me there is nothing you can do.
我也希望有 但很抱歉
I wish there was. I am sorry.
卫生部的
NHS.
他们怎么说?
What did they say?
任何人一但感染了
Anyone infected.
死亡率是100%
It's a 100% mortality rate.
今天
You know, today,
当米歇尔对查佩尔说因为我的伤势我应该留守时
when Michelle told Chappelle that I should stand down because of my wound,
我甚至没和她说话
I barely even spoke to her.
听着 托尼 对你的遭遇我虽然不能感同身受
Look, Tony. I can't tell you that I know what you are going through because I don't.
但如果你有什么需要 我会帮你的
But if you need anything, I am here.
金 回避一下好吗?
Kim, would you excuse us?
当然 这是你要的文件
Of course, here's the file.
谢谢
Thanks.
你把这些资料都发给总部了吗?
Have you cleaned those shared files with Division yet?
没有 我还没开始弄
No, I didn't get to it yet.
我有别的事情
I had to take care of something.
我知道你在干什么 托尼
Yeah, I know what you were doing, Tony.
你在问关于米歇尔的事
You were calling about Michelle.
她是我妻子 瑞恩
She is my wife, Ryan.
我能理解
I understand that.
但现在人员紧张成这个样子 我们不能应付...
But we're shorthanded as it is. We can't afford...
听着 我知道怎么做事 好吗?
Look, I know how to do my job, all right?
但你没有这么做
Yes, but you are not doing it.
你必须振作
You have to move on.
振作?
Move on?
你怎么表现得像她已经死了一样?
What are you acting like she is already dead?
是的 我是这样想的
Yes, I am.
你也应该这样
And so should you.
这是一场战争 托尼
We're at war. Tony.
我需要你集中精神
I need your full attention.
如果你不能 就回家去 要不就去酒店那里守着
If you can't give it to me, go home or maintain a vigil at the hotel.
但如果你留在这里 就集中注意力
But if you stay here, I need you to focus.
你该做最坏的打算 化悲痛为力量 准备复仇
And the best way to do that is to assume the worst, and make it about getting revenge.
现在 你想怎么办?
Now, what's it going to be?
到底留不留下来?
Are you staying or not?
你要我做什么?
What do you need?
我正在调查从Go会所没收的电脑 搜寻所有阿马多尔过去几个月内
I have been hunting for any bank accounts Amador may have used over the past few months
可能使用的银行账户
on the computer we confiscated at the Go club.
如果有什么发现 也许我们能顺着资金流向找到这个斯蒂芬 桑德斯
If I can find something, maybe we can follow the money trail back to this Stephen Saunders.
海外帐号还是本土帐号?
It's offshore or domestic?
都查
Both
一有可疑 立刻通知你
If I find anything suspicious, I will stream it to you.
和总部联络准备地毯式搜索
Coordinate with Division on a substrata overlay.
好吧 我听你的
All right you got it
谢谢 托尼
Thanks, Tony
嗯
Yeah.
别开枪 我是联邦探员
Don't fire. I am a federal agent.
那又怎么样? 这是我家
So what? You are in my house.
别开枪 我只是想出示我的证件
Don't shoot. I just want to show you my identification.
你想干什么?
What do you want?
我想跟你谈谈斯蒂芬 桑德斯的事
I need to talk to you about Stephen Saunders.
混蛋
Bastard.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
你先
You first.
好吧
Ok
我现在把枪放下
I am gonna put my gun down.
放松点
Just take it easy.
走出来
Step out from behind there.
好 我出来了
Ok, I am coming out.
放松点
Just take it easy.
冷静
Stay calm
我只想和你谈谈
I just want to talk to you.
现在我们可以谈了
Now we can talk.
我先把衣服穿好行吗?
Do you mind if I get dressed first?
可以
Go ahead
说说你和桑德斯的事
Tell me about you and Saunders.
斯蒂芬总是说他会保护我
Stephen always told me he'd protect me.
我那时太年轻 傻乎乎的相信了他
I was young and stupid and I believed him.
但当我的工作不那么光彩的时候 他把我甩了
When the work turned ugly, he left me hanging.
什么工作?
What kind of work?
我们靠身体谋生
It's a figure of speech.
我们知道你通过你的那些女孩为斯蒂芬 桑德斯套取情报
We know you acquired intelligence for Stephen Saunders through your girls.
我给有钱人提供服务
I provided a service for wealthy men.
你觉得我背叛了他们 这生意会长久吗?
How long do you think that would have lasted if I betrayed their confidences?
这么说你否认替他做过事
So you're denying that you worked for him.
对
Yes.
我不相信
I don't believe you.
我不在乎你信不信
I don't care.
你会在乎的 来吧
You will. Come on.
蔡斯 给汤姆林森打电话
Chase, call Tomlinson.
告诉他我们把戴安娜·怀特带去审问
Tell him we are bringing Diana White in for questioning.
没见到律师之前 我哪也不去
I am not going anywhere without a lawyer.
你不是被逮捕
You are not under arrest.
我把你带到英国军情6处分部去 在那你会被一名外国政府特工审问
I am taking you in to MI-6, where you will be interrogated by an agent of a foreign government.
你的所有公民权利统统失效 走
Your constitutional rights no longer apply. Let's go.
你见到盖尔了吗?
Have you seen Gael?
他快不行了
He doesn't have much time left.
这么快
So fast.
他很痛苦吗?
Is he in a lot of pain?
米歇尔 你也知道这病毒
Michelle, you know the pathology of this virus.
我要见他
I want to see him.
最好别去
I wouldn't advise that.
如果我被感染了 我也是患者
If I have been infected, I have been infected.
谁也无能为力
There's nothing anyone can do.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
任何事都行
Anything.
联系我的家人 告诉她们我爱她们
Contact my family, and tell them that I love them.
告诉她们我死的很快
Tell them that I have died quickly.
没有痛苦
No pain.
一定
Of course.
盖尔.
Gael
我一直都认为自杀是一种罪孽
I was raised to believe suicide is a sin.
为了结束你的痛苦
No one could blame you,
不论今生还是来世 没人会责怪你
in this world or the next, for ending your suffering.
真的吗?
Are you so sure about that?
再给我几秒钟 我只要几秒钟
A few seconds more, that's all I needed.
你知道吗...
You know...
当我试图解除爆炸物时
when I was trying to stop the cylinder from exploding,
我犹豫了 就那么一下
I hesitated, just a moment,
因为我害怕了
because I was afraid.
然后我逼着自己上前
Then I forced myself to move forward.
假如我没有犹豫
If only I hadn't hesitated,
那这一切都不会发生在我
this might not be happening to me,
以及楼下那些可怜的人身上了
or to all those poor people upstairs.
天哪
God.
盖尔 你已经尽力了
Gael, you did everything you could.
能和你共事是我的荣幸
I am proud to have worked with you.
你是我见过...
You're one of...
你是我见过最勇敢的人
You are one of the bravest men I have ever known.
我相信你的妻子女儿也会了解
And I will make sure that your wife and children know that.
国土安全部已经把警报等级提高到红色
Homeland security has raised the threat level to red.
现在 他们正不断和联邦调查局联系
Now, they are in constant contact with the FBI, set to move
研究 "灭顶之灾" 会不会引发任何可疑行动
if "the sky is falling" should trigger any kind of suspicious activity.
航空局有没有迫降所有飞机并关闭机场?
Is the FAA set to ground flights and close the airports?
大卫 我觉得这样有点过了
David, I think that's an overreaction.
这不是我要的答案
That was not my question.
已经下令了
Yes.
女士们先生们 有请美国总统
Ladies and gentlemen, the President of the United States.
请坐
Please, be seated.
早上好
Good morning.
我知道此刻非比寻常
I know the hour is unusual,
但这个时期也是非比寻常的
but so are the timesyi in which we live.
据国土安全部及其他部门收集的情报显示
As a result of intelligence on terrorist activity,
恐怖分子正酝酿袭击
gathered by the office of Homeland Security and other agencies,
我现在宣布全国都保持红色预警
I am announcing that a threat level red exists throughout the United States.
因此 我命令取消所有国内和国际航班
Therefore, I am ordering the grounding of all domestic and international air traffic,
关闭机场
and the closing of airports.
我做此决定并非因为灭顶之灾就在眼前
I am not taking this action because the sky is falling,
我宁愿未雨绸缪也不愿被打个措手不及
but I'd rather be overprotective than underprepared.
一如既往 细心和冷静是我们对付阴险的最好武器
And as always, diligence and calm are your best weapons against the insidious nature of the enemy.
上帝保佑 我们以及所有热爱自由的人们会平安无事
And God willing, we and all those who love freedom will remain safe and secure.
感谢大家
Thank you.
总统先生 我能问个问题吗?
Mr President, can I have a question, please?
不好意思 不好意思
Excuse me, excuse me.
没有安排问答的时间
This is not a Q and A session.
总统已经作出声明 他也没什么需要补充的
The president has made a statement, and he has nothing more to add.
非常感谢大家
Thank you very much.
等一下
One moment.
就几个问题
Maybe a couple of questions.
总统先生
Mr. President.
菲尔.
Phil
美国当前是否正遭受袭击?
Is the United States currently under attack?
这只是预防措施
This is a preventive measure.
预防什么呢?
What are you preventing, sir?
还有关闭所有航线的理由含糊
And do you think the American public will accept the grounding of air traffic
你觉得美国公众是否会接受?
based on the rather vague justification you have just given?
袭击的具体性质我暂时不能透露
The exact nature of the threat is something I can't go into at this time.
你好 杰克
Hello, Jack.
特雷弗 这位是我的搭档蔡斯·埃德蒙兹
Trevor, this is my partner, Chase Edmunds.
蔡斯·埃德蒙兹 这位是特雷弗·汤姆林森
Chase Edmunds, Trevor Tomlinson
还有这位是戴安娜·怀特女士
And this is Ms Diana White.
怀特女士
Ms White.
我们又做了些调查
We've done some additional checking.
她是桑德斯上次在唐人街露面的那所房子的主人
She is the registered owner of the address in Chinatown where Saunders was last seen.
但我没见过他
But I haven't seen him.
你最好考虑清楚 怀特女士
You might want to think that through, Ms White.
你觉得他会为你做同样的事吗?
Do you think he'd put himself on the line like this for you?
我们正着手调查收集的桑德斯的原始资料
We've begun vetting the raw data we collected on Saunders.
你把这些传给伦敦方面了吗?
You sent it off to London yet?
还没有 仍在楼下的电脑里
No. It's still in our system downstairs.
伦敦方面要我们在传送之前尽可能深入的调查一下
London wants us to get as far as we can before transmitting.
趴下
Get down.
蔡斯 你中弹了?
Chase, are you hit?
擦身而过
I got it in the vest.
掩护我
Cover me.
特雷弗 那些关于桑德斯的资料 存在哪个服务器上?
Trevor, the Saunders computer file. What server did you store it on?
A5.
A5
我们得到电脑房去
We have got to get down to the computer room.
走楼梯 快
Use the stairs. Go.
桑德斯这次行动绝不仅仅是为了杀了戴安娜·怀特
There's no way that Saunders took out this entire place just to kill Diana White.
军情6处有其他地方没有的资料
MI-6 has information in their systems that doesn't exist anywhere else in the world.
我们得拿到
We need to get it.
我来开门
I'll get the door.
房内安全
Room is clear.
看一下他
Check him out.
蔡斯.
Chase
怎么了?
What?
有炸弹
We got a bomb.
还有多少时间?
How much time?
没了 你得马上离开
None. You got to go now.
快走!
Go now!
杰克 我不会丢下你的
Jack, I am not leaving you.
快出去
Get out of here.
这是命令 快走
It's an order. Go now.
拿到了 快走 快 快
I got it. Go, go, go.
阿尔梅达.
Almeida
托尼 是我
Tony, it's me.
盖尔死了
Gael is dead.
他死的时候非常痛苦
He was suffering so badly.
谁都不该承受他所承受的痛苦
No one should have to go through what he did.
托尼 楼上还有些孩子也将这么痛苦的死去
Tony, there are children upstairs who are going to die in agony.
就在他们父母的眼前
in front of their parents' eyes.
米歇尔 非常不幸 我们也帮不了他们
Michelle, unfortunately, there's nothing we can do for them right now.
其实 可以
Actually, there is.
野战部队有一种胶囊
Field Ops has a supply of capsules.
那是给那些野外作战被俘的特工用的
Those capsules are for field agents that are captured.
对 我知道那是干什么用的
Yeah, I know what they are for.
用来自杀防止被酷刑折磨 现在这场合非常合适
They are for committing suicide to prevent torture, and that's exactly what they'd be used for here.
我们可以把它们发给发病的人
We can make them available to anyone who's symptomatic.
他们会心甘情愿的
It will be their choice.
你也知道我无权这么做
You know I am not authorized to do that.
我对谁有权力不感兴趣
I am not interested in what's authorized.
米歇尔 你这是以一个联邦探员的身份怂恿大量的人自杀
Michelle, you are talking about mass suicide facilitated by an agency of the government.
我是给他们应有的尊重
I am talking about common decency.
如果你看到了盖尔的样子...
If you could have seen Gael...
我给你打电话是因为...
I am calling because...
如果是我
if it was me,
如果我感染了
if I am infected,
你知道我想要什么
You know what I want.
我们的时间不多了
We don't have much time.
盖尔第一个死亡是因为他是第一个接触的 但其他人也快了
Gael was the first to die because he was the first exposed, but others won't be far behind.
我看看我能做些什么
I will see what I can do.
谢谢
Thank you.
查佩尔先生 2号线
Mr Chappelle, line 2.
我是查佩尔
Chappelle.
瑞恩 我是杰克
Ryan, it's Jack.
几乎整个军情6处都被毁了
Almost the entire MI-6 office has just been wiped out.
什么?
What?
他们杀了那个我们认为近期曾和桑德斯联系过的女人
They took out a woman that we believe had recent contact with Saunders.
他们还杀了大部分工作人员 包括汤姆林森
They also took out most of their personnel, including Tomlinson, which means that Saunders
这说明桑德斯在洛杉矶的组织比我们想象的庞大
has a much larger organization in Los Angeles than we had thought.
但也意味着更明显 更容易找
But it also makes them more visible, easier to find.
你那有什么线索?
Have you got anything yet?
还没
I don't know.
我正在追踪资金流向
I am trying to follow the money trail.
我已经将范围缩小到若干个海外银行了 但还需要点时间
I have narrowed it down to a few dozen offshore banks, but it's going to take some time.
好 听着  桑德斯试图毁掉的东西中有军情6处收集的关于他的资料
Ok, look, one of the things that Saunders was trying to destroy was all the information that MI-6 had gathered on him.
我想办法抢回了存储这些资料的硬盘
I managed to retrieve the hard drive that has stored that information.
我要你给伦敦方面打电话 跟他们协调
I need you to call London, get their protocols and I want you to assemble a team
希望我回来的时候你能召集足够的人来筛选这些资料
that's ready to start striping data off of this thing as soon as I get back.
好 我让克萝伊马上去办
All right, I will put Chloe on it right away.
好
Ok.
给那些酒店的人准备的自杀胶囊
The suicide capsules for the people down at the hotel.
他们会很惨
It's going to get pretty bad down there.
这违反规定
It's against every regulation in the book.
对
Yeah.
就这么办吧
Do it.
我试着给帕克打电话 但没人接
I've been trying to call Pack, but there's no answer.
他死了 杨也是
He's dead. So is Young.
死在军情6处
Taken out in the MI-6 operation.
鲍尔呢?
And Bauer?
他和他的搭档在爆炸前逃了出来
He and his partner got out before the explosion.
那些硬盘全被摧毁了么?
But the hard drive was completely destroyed?
全部
Completely.
黛安娜呢?
What about Diana?
死了
Dead.
我会想念她的
I will miss her.
还有件事
There is one more thing.
有人在调查开曼银行
There have been some inquiries made about the bank in Cayman.
谁?
By whom?
反恐局的
They're coming from CTU.
一个叫瑞恩·查佩尔的
A man named Ryan Chappelle.
我认识查佩尔
I know Chappelle.
很显然 他很擅长追踪资金的流向
Apparently, he's quite good at following money trails.
是吗?
Is he?
继续接下来的计划
Carry on.
我会向总统汇报
I will tell the president.
什么事?
What is it?
有人袭击了英国军情6处洛杉矶办事处
There was just an attack on the L.A. office of MI-6.
杰克·鲍尔也在场
Jack Bauer was there at the time.
他没事吧?
Is he all right?
没事 他在回反恐局的路上
Yes. He's on his way back to CTU.
有没有迹象表明是我在记者招待会上说的话触发了这次袭击?
Any indication that the attack was triggered by what I said at the press conference?
大卫 我们不清楚什么引发了这次袭击
David, we don't know what triggered the attack.
也许正是我的话引起的
So it could have been what I said.
他们怎么袭击的?
How was the attack carried out?
用直升机 里面有两个人
By helicopter, and 2 men inside.
那他们可以降落在任何地方
All right, so they have to land it somewhere.
命令航空局与国土安全局及边境巡逻队联合行动
I want FAA to coordinate with homeland security and border patrol.
我这就去办 总统先生
Right away, Mr President.
什么事?
What?
我很喜欢你的记者招待会 总统先生
I enjoyed your press conference, Mr President.
很高兴获悉灭顶之灾的事
It's good to know the sky's not falling.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
给你下一个任务
To give you your next assignment.
在正式下达任务之前有些小问题要解决
A sort of preliminary action to clear the decks before the main event to come.
有个叫瑞恩·查佩尔的 反恐局的地区主管
There's a man named Ryan Chappelle. Regional director of CTU.
对 他怎么了?
Yeah, what about him?
我要他死
I want him killed.
什么?
What?
早上七点 把他的尸体送到市区火车站的主轨旁边
At 7:00 am. Have his body delivered to the train yard downtown just off the main line.
在你决定前 最好去钱德勒 广场酒店参观一下
Before you decide, you might want to drop by the Chandler Plaza Hotel.
看看都发生了什么
Take a good look at what's happening.
再想象一下全国各地发生同样的事
Then imagine the same event taking place at hundreds of locations all over the country.
你疯了
You are insane.
他想要什么?
What does he want?
大卫?
David?